eircode.ie 2015-11-20

# Eircode Privacy Policy

### Website of Eircode

This statement relates to our privacy practices in connection with this website. We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other websites. Any external links to other websites are clearly identifiable as such. 

### Protecting the privacy of customers and users

We take care to protect the privacy of customers and users of this website. Set out below is an explanation of how we process information about visitors to the site.  Capita Business Support Services, Ireland (Capita) will not collect any personal information about you on this website without your clear permission. Any personal information which you volunteer to  Capita will be treated with the highest standards of security and confidentiality, strictly in accordance with the Irish Data Protection Acts, 1988 & 2003.

### Collection of personal information

The information which we collect and store during normal use of the site is used to monitor and analyse how parts of the site are used. 

You may have the option on certain pages within this site to submit personal information to Capita, in order to be able to manage your correspondence or complaints, or in order that we might send you further information or email alerts. These pages provide explanations as to how this personal information is to be used.

We will not disclose any personal information we collect about you when you visit the site to a third party outside Capita, without your consent. 

In connection with any application, request, complaint or enquiry you make, your information will be passed directly to the relevant business unit within Capita. 

By submitting your personal information through this website, you shall be consenting to it being processed in the manner described above by Capita.

If you have submitted personal information through this website and wish us to cease using it for the purposes submitted, please email sales@eircode.ie outlining your request. Capita will respond as quickly as possible to your preference.

### Cookie Policy 

We use a minimal number of different cookies on our site. Cookies are small text files that an organisation can use on its website in order to ‘recognise’ visitors who revisit a site so as to manage and improve their ongoing access to and use of the site. 

The cookie also enables the organisation to track and evaluate visitor behaviour, and compiles aggregate data that helps the organisation to improve the ‘visitor experience’ and web-site content.

Typically, cookies involve the assigning of a unique number to the visitor. If you do not want cookies to be assigned to you during your visit to our web-site, one simple way to prevent the use of cookies is to use the option, available in most web browsers, that enables the visitor to decline or disable cookies.

However, visitors should realise that certain cookies may be necessary in order to provide the visitor with certain features such as the customised delivery of certain information, These are known as ‘session cookies’, and cannot be disabled, as they are necessary for your use of the web-site. These cookies will disable as soon as you leave the web-site.

The list below describes the cookies we use on this site and what we use them for. By continuing to visit our web-site, we understand that you consent to our use of these cookies. If you are not happy, then you should either not use this site, or you should delete the cookies having visited the site, or you should browse the site using your browser’s anonymous usage setting (called “Incognito” in Chrome, “InPrivate” for Internet Explorer, “Private Browsing” in Firefox and Safari etc.)

### First Party Cookies

These are cookies that are set by this website directly.

Google Analytics: We use Google Analytics to collect information about visitor behaviour on our website. Google Analytics stores information about what pages you visit, how long you are on the site, how you got here and what you click on. This Analytics data is collected via a JavaScript tag in the pages of our site and is not tied to personally identifiable information.  We do not collect or store your your name or address as part of this data.

You can find out more about Google’s position on privacy as regards its analytics service at <http://www.google.ie/policies/privacy/>or to opt out please follow this link <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

### Third Party Cookies

These are cookies set on your machine by external websites whose services are used on this site. Cookies of this type are the sharing buttons across the site allow visitors to share content onto social networks. Cookies are currently set by Twitter, Facebook, YouTube. In order to implement these buttons, and connect them to the relevant social networks and external sites, there are scripts from domains outside of our website. You should be aware that these sites are likely to be collecting information about what you are doing all around the internet, including on this website.

You should check the respective policies of each of these sites to see how exactly they use your information and to find out how to opt out, or delete, such information.
